<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Viktor Elias</title>
    <link href="https://viktorelias.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://viktorelias.com" />
    <updated>2022-10-17T19:47:40-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Viktor Elias</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://viktorelias.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Taylor Swift Makes &#x27;Red (Taylor&#x27;s Version)&#x27; Even Better</title>
        <author>
            <name>Viktor Elias</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://viktorelias.com/taylor-swift-makes-red-taylors-version-even-better/"/>
        <id>https://viktorelias.com/taylor-swift-makes-red-taylors-version-even-better/</id>
            <category term="JRN 501"/>

        <updated>2022-10-17T19:47:18-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/4/taylor-swift-red-tour.jpeg" alt="Taylor Swift performs at the Red Tour in March 2013" />
                    Nearly 10 years after its initial release as Taylor Swift’s fourth studio album, Red (Taylor’s Version) manages to be even better than the original. Running just over two hours long, her album features the re-recordings of the original 21 songs from the album and its&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/4/taylor-swift-red-tour.jpeg" alt="Taylor Swift performs at the Red Tour in March 2013" />
                
  <p>
    Nearly 10 years after its initial release as Taylor Swift’s fourth studio album, <em>Red (Taylor’s Version)</em> manages to be even better than the original. Running just over two hours long, her album features the re-recordings of the original 21 songs from the album and its subsequent era, plus nine new songs. <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22278732/taylor-swift-re-recording-fearless-love-story-master-rights-scooter-braun" target="_blank">Being the second album she has re-recorded in the long process to regain ownership of her masters, it has a lot going for it.</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    Nominated for album of the year at the 2013 Grammys, <em>Red</em> was one of her most successful albums to date. The album marked her transition to mainstream pop, as her songs strayed away from her typical country sound. With songs featuring heartbreak, <a href="https://taylorswift.tumblr.com/post/654352493514473472/ive-always-said-that-the-world-is-a-different" target="_blank">Swift described the album as a “fractured mosaic of feelings”</a> as she entered her early 20s.
  </p>

  <p>
    The album featured major hits like “I Knew You Were Trouble” and “We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together,” but also iconic breakup song and fan-favourite “All Too Well.” With its fair share of hits, it seemed the new re-recordings were going to garner a wide audience of fans old and new, creating lots of anticipation for its release. The album lives up to that anticipation, expanding even further in its maturity and sound than we could have expected.
  </p>

  <p>
    Being an album almost 10 years old, it is incredible to hear the voice of a more mature Swift reflect on the feelings of the past in the re-recorded <em>Red (Taylor’s Version)</em>. Her maturity is clear across the album in her voice and in the production of the songs, making her music even better — a common theme across her re-recordings.
  </p>

  <p>
    During the process of re-recording her songs, Swift is liberated to do as she pleases with her songs. An almost feminist perspective, the re-recordings allow her to produce the songs the way she wanted them to original sound and not the way some recording label executives wanted. Even on “Girl at Home,” which is considered one of the weaker songs on the album, she adds a more poppy and upbeat sound that gets rid of its original country sound. The re-recordings allow her fans, both new and old, to appreciate one of the songs widely considered one of her worst. By tweaking her original songs, she contributes to an improvement of her own album.
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sRxrwjOtIag" target="_blank">“All Too Well”</a>&nbsp;is a perfect example of this, as <a href="https://www.thefader.com/2021/11/22/taylor-swifts-10-minute-all-too-well-breaks-record-for-longest-hot-100-no-1#:~:text=The%20original%20version%20of%20the%20song%20was%20released%20in%202012.&amp;text=At%20just%20over%2010%2Dminutes,37%20seconds%2C%20and%20was%20No." target="_blank" class="" data-link-popup-id="1665682846148">the highly anticipated 10-minute version charted at number one on the Billboard Hot 100</a>, making it the longest song ever to hit that position. The longer version, which includes verses and lyrics not included in the original, gives it way more elegance and meaning. It contains some of her most touching lyrics to date as she sings, “They say all's well that ends well, but I'm in a new hell / Every time you double-cross my mind.” Without a doubt, the 10 minute and 13-second song ties the entire album together and makes it even better than it already was.
  </p>

  <p>
    Overall, <em>Red (Taylor’s Version)</em> celebrates her growth, both in her personal and professional life, as she perpetually improves her craft. Being able to make an iconic pop album even better shows her talent is unmatched.&nbsp;<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>2016 U.S. Presidential Debate: Donald Trump vs. Hillary Clinton: A Political Analysis</title>
        <author>
            <name>Viktor Elias</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://viktorelias.com/2016-us-presidential-debate-donald-trump-vs-hillary-clinton-a-political-analysis/"/>
        <id>https://viktorelias.com/2016-us-presidential-debate-donald-trump-vs-hillary-clinton-a-political-analysis/</id>
            <category term="JRN 501"/>

        <updated>2022-10-17T19:46:35-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/1/2016-us-presidential-debate.jpeg" alt="Preparations for 2016 U.S. Presidential Debate between Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton" />
                    During the first 2016 U.S. presidential election debate, Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton faced off in a sometimes heated debate that revolved around a number of key issues. Compared to the 2020 U.S. presidential election debate between Donald Trump and Joe Biden, it’s clear the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/1/2016-us-presidential-debate.jpeg" alt="Preparations for 2016 U.S. Presidential Debate between Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the first <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=855Am6ovK7s" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2016 U.S. presidential election debate</a>, Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton faced off in a sometimes heated debate that revolved around a number of key issues. Compared to the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5cathmZFeXs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2020 U.S. presidential election debate</a> between Donald Trump and Joe Biden, it’s clear the temperature has changed for the worse in the U.S., at least within the political system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Donald, I know you live in your own reality,” said Clinton in the highly-anticipated event hosted at Hofstra University in Hempstead, New York, suggesting Trump lies. She also suggested he was and is a racist and a sexist. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Throughout the debate, Clinton called Trump by his first name — a sign of the lack of collegiality that has seeped into recent U.S. politics, including but not limited to the first U.S. presidential debate during the 2020 cycle between Biden and Trump where Biden asked the then-U.S. president Trump to “shut up.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sharpest exchanges in the 2016 debate, however, involved issues of race and gender.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/05/birtherism-and-trump/610978/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trump avoided explaining his support for “birtherism,”</a> falsely accusing Clinton partisans of spreading it during the 2008 Democratic primaries. He also avoided explaining why he suddenly <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2016/09/donald-trump-birtherism-campaign-statement-228261" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced</a>, earlier in the month, that he now believes former U.S. president Barack Obama was born in Hawaii, after years of suggesting otherwise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the 2020 debate, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/29/us/trump-proud-boys-biden.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trump took the race issue and ignited it on fire when he told the Proud Boys, a white supremacist group, to “stand back and stand by”</a> while denouncing left-wing groups like Antifa — something that exemplifies the ways in which the political temperature and conversation, at official events like debates, has been dialed way up since the 2016 debate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clinton, in fairness, said Trump built his entire political career by promoting the claim that Obama was not an American citizen, calling it a “racist lie,” during the 2016 debate. Noting <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/28/us/politics/donald-trump-housing-race.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trump’s company was sued for housing discrimination back in the 1970s</a>, Clinton said he “has a long record of engaging in racist behaviour.” Trump answered by saying the Justice Department was suing a number of other companies for racial discrimination at the time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trump did not retract previous comments that said Clinton lacked “the look” and “the stamina” to be president. In additional comments which likely referred to her health, Trump said “I don’t believe Hillary has the stamina” to endure the burdens of the presidency.” Clinton fought back and suggested that when Trump travels to more than 100 countries, engages in marathon testimony to congressional committees, then “he can talk to me about stamina.” Throughout the debate, <a href="https://www.cosmopolitan.com/uk/reports/a42442/donald-trump-women-sexist-quotes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Clinton made it a point to bring attention to Trump’s past unpresidential comments, including his past references to looks, arguing that “this is a man who calls women pigs, slobs, and dogs.”</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, the debate was very much effective in that it showed the ways in which the temperature has heated up since 2016, but it also vindicated Clinton, especially in regards to her comments about Trump’s taxes, in which she suggested he paid none. (<a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/09/27/politics/trump-income-taxes-new-york-times-report/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The New York Times confirmed this in a 2020 report.</a>) But the real loser in this debate was the American people, who have lost the civility that once ruled their politics, and in the broader public sphere.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Toronto, in Red Zone, Moves to Extend COVID-19 Restrictions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Viktor Elias</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://viktorelias.com/toronto-in-red-zone-moves-to-extend-covid-19-restrictions/"/>
        <id>https://viktorelias.com/toronto-in-red-zone-moves-to-extend-covid-19-restrictions/</id>
            <category term="JRN 103"/>

        <updated>2022-10-17T19:47:40-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/7/toronto-covid-pandemic.jpeg" alt="Woman crosses the street in Downtown Toronto" />
                    Toronto’s top doctor announced on Tuesday that the city will move into the red zone of Ontario’s COVID-19 tiered shutdown system and will tighten restrictions even further, including postponing the resumption of indoor dining until at least mid-December. Toronto Medical Officer of Health Dr. Eileen&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/7/toronto-covid-pandemic.jpeg" alt="Woman crosses the street in Downtown Toronto" />
                
  <p>
    <a href="https://www.toronto.ca/news/city-of-toronto-mandating-stricter-restrictions-to-decrease-covid-19-transmission-in-toronto/" target="_blank">Toronto’s top doctor announced on Tuesday</a> that the city will move into the red zone of Ontario’s COVID-19 tiered shutdown system and will tighten restrictions even further, including postponing the resumption of indoor dining until at least mid-December.<br><br><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=py2UgAJdgcw" target="_blank">Toronto Medical Officer of Health Dr. Eileen de Villa announced the restrictions as the city recorded its highest number of new COVID-19 infections on Tuesday</a>, with 533 new cases in the previous 24-hour period. De Villa also suggested that all residents restrict all social gatherings with people who live outside their own home, just as the city moves into the red phase of the province’s shutdown system on Nov. 14, the last step before a full lockdown.<br><br>The additional restrictions she announced also include a ban on indoor fitness classes, with gyms only allowed to operate if there are fewer than 10 people indoors at one time. Toronto will also require the continued closure of meeting and event spaces, including casinos and bingo halls, among other gaming and entertainment establishments like movie theatres.<br><br>“I know the vast majority of people support doing everything we can in order to confront COVID-19 and get our lives back to normal,” Toronto Mayor John Tory said on Tuesday at a press conference. “We need your help right now to do just that.”<br><br>De Villa said the restrictions are expected to remain in place for 28 days, starting on Nov. 14, meaning the earliest businesses could reopen is on Dec. 12. The red zone of Ontario’s COVID-19 framework does not require indoor dining to close, but Toronto has decided to do so. “I want to warn you in the plainest possible terms, COVID-19 is out there at levels that we have not seen before,” de Villa said on Tuesday at a press conference. “The trend is upward.”<br><br>“What’s best for our local economy is also what is best for the health and safety of our residents: Businesses can’t thrive when COVID-19 is surging,” said Toronto City Councillor and Chair of the Toronto Board of Health&nbsp;Joe Cressy on Tuesday at the same press conference. “Business owners and employees deserve to have a reopening that doesn’t put themselves or their customers at risk and that’s sustainable.”<br><br>"I recognize that these actions will have economic impacts and I am truly sorry for this, I really am. However, in my professional opinion, the greatest harm would be to allow COVID-19 to continue to spread at this rate,” de Villa said.<br><br>Over the past four days, the city added nearly 2,000 new cases, according to the city’s COVID-19 database. Toronto’s COVID-19 test positivity rate has also spiked to 5.9 per cent. “You should assume it is everywhere,” de Villa said. “Without proper precautions and protections, you are at risk of infection.”<br><br>Peel Region is the only other region in the province to have been placed in the red category of Ontario’s tiered system. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZcoMgUaDWOk" target="_blank">Peel Region Medical Officer of Health Dr. Lawrence Loh announced the restrictions over the weekend</a>, adding further restrictions on indoor dining and gym activity and calls for residents not to interact with people outside their households.<br><br>“Our hospitals are transferring patients all over Ontario,” said Loh on Monday. “That means our healthcare system in Peel is at capacity, beyond capacity.”
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Ford Announces Millions in Mental Health, Addictions Supports</title>
        <author>
            <name>Viktor Elias</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://viktorelias.com/ford-announces-millions-in-mental-health-addictions-supports/"/>
        <id>https://viktorelias.com/ford-announces-millions-in-mental-health-addictions-supports/</id>
            <category term="JRN 103"/>

        <updated>2022-10-17T19:47:33-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/6/doug-ford.jpeg" alt="Doug Ford speaks to a crowd of supporters" />
                    The COVID-19 pandemic has been stressful for many, but for others it has been deadly. Across Ontario, there has been a significant increase in overdose deaths, coinciding with the lockdown and other social distancing measures announced at the beginning of the pandemic. Between January and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/6/doug-ford.jpeg" alt="Doug Ford speaks to a crowd of supporters" />
                
  <p>
    The COVID-19 pandemic has been stressful for many, but for others it has been deadly.<br><br>Across Ontario, there has been a significant increase in overdose deaths, coinciding with the lockdown and other social distancing measures announced at the beginning of the pandemic. <a href="https://health-infobase.canada.ca/substance-related-harms/opioids/maps?index=1" target="_blank">Between January and March, Ontario reported 446 opioid-related deaths</a>, according to the federal government’s database. On Wednesday, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RNFWjfw3pk8" target="_blank">Ontario Premier Doug Ford announced an additional round of funding</a> to help expand access to mental health and addictions supports. <a href="https://www.ontario.ca/page/roadmap-wellness-plan-build-ontarios-mental-health-and-addictions-system" target="_blank">The $176 million announced is part of the province’s A Roadmap to Wellness plan</a>, which includes $3.8 billion of funding over 10 years to deliver high-quality mental health supports.<br><br>“Today’s ongoing investment not only delivers on our government’s historic commitment to invest billions in mental health over 10 years, but it will also provide care for thousands of people, including frontline health workers and first responders, who need such critical supports during these challenging times,” Ford said.<br><br><a href="https://news.ontario.ca/en/release/58717/ontario-building-a-modern-connected-and-comprehensive-mental-health-and-additions-system" target="_blank">To enable the plan, the province is investing billions</a> to create and expand services and programs to fill-in the urgent gaps in care, such as:
  </p>

  <ol>
    <li>$4 million in funding for nurse practitioners for detox services to be used to improve the medical management of clients, many of whom are struggling with addictions and mental health, at residential withdrawal management facilities.</li><li>$8 million in funding for addictions care to be used to increase access to intensive non-residential addictions and substance use treatment services for youth and adults.</li><li>$3.5 million for withdrawal management services to be used to increase access to in-home and community withdrawal management services for hard-to-service clients, such as those in rural areas and Indigenous communities.</li>
  </ol>

  <p>
    "By making these investments, our government is making it easier for people to find and access high-quality mental health and addictions services when and where they need them," said Ontario Health Minister Christine Elliott. "We're working across government and with system partners to provide long-term stability and investments in critical services to improve and modernize the system and close urgent gaps in care."<br><br><a href="http://www.camh.ca/en/camh-news-and-stories/camh-marks-completion-of-phase-1c-redevelopment-project" target="_blank">Wednesday’s announcement was at CAMH, which celebrated the grand opening of the third phase of their redevelopment project</a>, which included the McCain Complex Care and Recovery Building that will be used to promote recovery and integration into the community for patients in a connected and coordinated system of care and the Crisis and Critical Care Building that will be used to house Ontario’s first 24/7 emergency department dedicated to mental health.<br><br>"I thank the government for investing in this transformation. The CAMH redevelopment is a symbol of progress – respectful and dignified spaces that support the best in crisis and complex mental health care,” said CAMH President and CEO Dr. Catherine Zahn. “We look forward to working with the government to bring health equity to people living with mental illness."<br><br>The province has now contributed more than $350 million to the sector.<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Fact Check: Was Joe Biden &quot;Wearing a Wire&quot; During the Debate?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Viktor Elias</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://viktorelias.com/fact-check-was-joe-biden-wearing-a-wire-during-the-debate/"/>
        <id>https://viktorelias.com/fact-check-was-joe-biden-wearing-a-wire-during-the-debate/</id>
            <category term="JRN 103"/>

        <updated>2022-10-17T19:47:26-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/5/joe-biden.jpeg" alt="Joe Biden " />
                    Tuesday's U.S. presidential debate was one to remember. Both candidates — U.S. President Donald J. Trump and former Vice-President Joe Biden — took turns knocking each other in the 90-minute event. In numerous videos posted to social media, users pointed out that it appeared as&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://viktorelias.com/media/posts/5/joe-biden.jpeg" alt="Joe Biden " />
                
  <p>
    Tuesday's U.S. presidential debate was one to remember. Both candidates — U.S. President Donald J. Trump and former Vice-President Joe Biden — took turns knocking each other in the 90-minute event.
  </p>

  <p>
    In numerous videos posted to social media, users pointed out that it appeared as though Biden was "wearing a wire." Although the claims are unsubstantiated, it appears as though some users believe this as fact, even after a rebuttal from Biden's campaign team.
  </p>

  <p>
    This comes days after Trump erroneously claimed that Biden would be wearing a wire or an earpiece during the debate. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-09-29/trump-biden-campaigns-spar-over-earpieces-before-debate?utm_source=facebook&amp;cmpid=socialflow-facebook-politics&amp;utm_content=politics&amp;utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;fbclid=IwAR1-RV8sQ5TROU2yoFmKVOhddiKyituDzrQ6bdw4sNNjM5nk2oozJpS9HqM" target="_blank">Biden's deputy campaign manager Kate Bedingfield decried the claims, saying, "Of course he is not wearing an earpiece."</a><br>
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://archive.st/archive/2020/10/www.facebook.com/6vjt/www.facebook.com/shaun.brandon07/posts/1676664602510276.html" target="_blank" class="" data-link-popup-id="1665787758394">In one video that was shared thousands of times on Facebook alone, a grainy recording shows Biden putting his hand underneath his suit jacket, leading the camera to zoom-in and show Biden's shirt.</a> "There it is, there it is. Biden's wearing a wire," the male user who posted the video, says. "Why do you need a wire, bro?"
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yHFI8TsSKXY&amp;feature=emb_title" target="_blank" class="" data-link-popup-id="1665787768591">In one of the higher quality videos, the so-called "wire" is actually just a crease in Biden's shirt.</a> That did not stop many from taking to social media to spread the claim, with <a href="https://archive.is/e6bgg" target="_blank">one video racking up more than 15,000 views</a> and the <a href="https://archive.is/2GVIE#selection-3013.139-3023.24" target="_blank">hashtag #JoeWired spreading on Twitter.</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    Additional posts spread the same falsehood.
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://archive.is/YTgvX" target="_blank">"Was Biden wearing a wire?" read one meme posted to Facebook, having been shared over 7,500 times.</a> <a href="https://archive.is/Gv6CE" target="_blank">That post, coupled with the others, suggested the small object beneath the shirt cuff on his left wrist was something nefarious.</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://twitter.com/AynRandPaulRyan/status/1311277772430401537?s=20" target="_blank">It is possible the object was Biden's rosary</a>, which he often wears around his wrist <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/31/us/politics/joseph-r-biden-iii-vice-presidents-son-beau-dies-at-46.html" target="_blank">in honour of his late son, Beau, who passed away from brain cancer in 2015.</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=72oO7R0CxSo&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=124" target="_blank">"I have not taken off the rosary Beau was wearing when he passed, since then," Biden said in an interview with Megyn Kelly in 2017. "It's my connection with him."</a>
  </p>

  <p>
    It appears that the story is <strong>false</strong>, according to my analysis.<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
